

JESSE MCCALLUMS

Bolívar City, Venezuela +(58) 4121181409

Email: jessemccallums2001@gmail.com
LinkedIn: linkedin.com/in/jessemccallums/
GitHub: https://github.com/Jessemccallums

ABOUT ME

Creative, results-oriented junior software engineer with the work experiences and educational qualifications to conceive, design and execute multi-platform web and software solutions within project parameters. Possess a solid foundation in diverse programming, libraries, framework, and platform technologies. Partner with high-powered development teams to guide solution generation and delivery strategy. Outstanding communicator able to collect stakeholder and user requirements before translating them into exceptionally produced assets. Qualifications include full-stack development and bootcamp education and continuous software development learning.

EXPERIENCE

Full-Stack Developer, Sommelier's Web, July 2023 to November 2023

Buenos Aires, Argentina

- Collaborated with seven developers navigating the creation of a Wine and Whiskey e-commerce solution. In this project, we implemented different functionalities as a team. From Google authentication to User dashboard, from stripe implementation to mail notification. The approach was to create a holistic e-commerce to sell Whiskey and Wine through it.
- Spearheaded an entire stack approach of coding as tech lead, concentrating on the backend.
- Contributed to front-end development and met or exceeded goals by working together as a team.
- Played a key role in documenting and reporting on project progress and issues.
- Applied a strong understanding of the concepts regarding scalability, continuous integration, service-oriented architecture.

Full-Stack Developer, Risetalk, April 2023 - July 2023

Bogota, Colombia

- Charted a successful course for the development of an educational website in partnership with six developers.
- Planned and implemented new functions, including buying a course through Stripe, with a user dashboard, Search course functionality, Course Panel, and Leave a review of the course functionality.
- Delivered to the client a product that featured the ability to buy a course, complete the course, and earn a certification.
- As a tech lead, worked primarily with the front end, but also UX/UI design and some back-end functions.
- Worked as a team and independently to critically analyze problems and complete assigned tasks.
- Developed software solutions to assist in the production and delivery of website functions.

JESSE MCCALLUMS Page 2

Henry School, February 2023 to July 2023

Buenos Aires, Argentina

 Garnered excellent knowledge of front-end and back-end software engineering, including technologies such as HTML, CSS, JavaScript, React, React Router, React Redux, NodeJS, ExpressJS, Sequelize, SQL, PostgreSQL, Styled Components, NextJS, and TailwindCSS.

- Gained soft skills through a collaborative learning environment involving various development teams of 8
 members.
- Participated in mentorship pair programming and study sessions with other developers worldwide.

EDUCATION and CERTIFICATION

Henry School, Buenos Aires, Argentina, 2023 Full Stack Developer Certification, Comprehensive Training at Henry Bootcamp

Udemy, 2021

Udemy Courses Completion, Continuous Learning in Software Development

TECHNICAL PROFICIENCIES

- **Programming Languages, Libraries and Frameworks:** JavaScript, HTML, CSS, React, Redux, Tailwind CSS, Next.js, Node.js, Express.js, SQL, PostgreSQL, PHP, Laravel, Sequelize. MongoDB.
- Tools and Platforms: Figma, Notion, Git, GitHub, Vercel, WordPress, Insomnia, Webpack, Canva, Photoshop, Illustrator, UI/UX Design, Scrum, Trello, ChatGPT, Prompt Engineering

VOLUNTEERISM

Bethesda Academy, January 2023 to December 2023

Bolivar City, Venezuela

- Teaching HTML, CSS, and JavaScript to a group of 10 persons, from young boys of 14 years old to College students of 25 years old.
- Guiding in developing small projects for a group of learners.
- Delivering lectures about technology and software development.

ADDITIONAL INFORMATION

Languages: Spanish (native), English (C2), French, (B1), Chinese (HSK-2)

Interests: Running, documentaries, languages, self-development books, climbing, and facing new challenges